superxv.com 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy - Super Rugby | Super 15 Rugby and Rugby Championship News,Results and Fixtures from Super XV Rugby

**What is this Privacy Policy for?**  
This privacy policy is for this website [www.superxv.com](http://www.superxv.com/) and served by [Sports Digital Media Limited](http://www.sportsdm.com/) and governs the privacy of its users who choose to use it.

We take your privacy seriously and want you to understand our practices with respect to the handling of your personal data. This privacy statement explains how we do this.

The policy sets out the different areas where user privacy is concerned and outlines the obligations & requirements of the users, the website and website owners. Furthermore the way this website processes, stores and protects user data and information will also be detailed within this policy.

**The Website**  
This website and its owners take a proactive approach to user privacy and ensure the necessary steps are taken to protect the privacy of its users throughout their visiting experience. This website complies to all UK national laws and requirements for user privacy.

**Use of Cookies**  
This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Where applicable this website uses a cookie control system allowing the user on their first visit to the website to allow or disallow the use of cookies on their computer / device. This complies with recent legislation requirements for websites to obtain explicit consent from users before leaving behind or reading files such as cookies on a user’s computer / device.

Cookies are small files saved to the user’s computers hard drive that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website.  
Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.

This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy [here](http://www.google.com/privacy.html) for further information [ <http://www.google.com/privacy.html> ].  
Other cookies may be stored to your computers hard drive by external vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected.

**Contact & Communication**  
Users contacting this website and/or its owners do so at their own discretion and provide any such personal details requested at their own risk. Your personal information is kept private and stored securely until a time it is no longer required or has no use, as detailed in the Data Protection Act 1998. Every effort has been made to ensure a safe and secure form to email submission process but advise users using such form to email processes that they do so at their own risk.  
This website and its owners use any information submitted to provide you with further information about the products / services they offer or to assist you in answering any questions or queries you may have submitted. This includes using your details to subscribe you to any email newsletter program the website operates but only if this was made clear to you and your express permission was granted when submitting any form to email process. Or whereby you the consumer have previously purchased from or enquired about purchasing from the company a product or service that the email newsletter relates to. This is by no means an entire list of your user rights in regard to receiving email marketing material. Your details are not passed on to any third parties.

**External Links**  
Although this website only looks to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website. (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites, similar to; [www.rugbyweek.com](http://www.rugbyweek.com/) or [Rugby Week](http://www.rugbyweek.com/).)

The owners of this website cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

**Adverts and Sponsored Links**  
This website may contain sponsored links and adverts. These will typically be served through our advertising partners, to whom may have detailed privacy policies relating directly to the adverts they serve.

Clicking on any such adverts will send you to the advertisers website through a referral program which may use cookies and will track the number of referrals sent from this website. This may include the use of cookies which may in turn be saved on your computers hard drive. Users should therefore note they click on sponsored external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

**Social Media Platforms**  
Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. This website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.

This website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

**Shortened Links in Social Media**  
This website and its owners through their social media platform accounts may share web links to relevant web pages. By default some social media platforms shorten lengthy urls [web addresses] .  
Users are advised to take caution and good judgement before clicking any shortened urls published on social media platforms by this website and its owners. Despite the best efforts to ensure only genuine urls are published many social media platforms are prone to spam and hacking and therefore this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any shortened links.

### How long do we keep your information?

We will only hold your information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected, before making it non-identifiable or deleting it.

If you send us any ‘contact us’ messages, we will delete or de-identify these messages once we have finally satisfied your query.

If you choose to unsubscribe from a service, we may keep a ‘suppression list’ containing your details so we know you have unsubscribed.

### When we collect your personal data

If you decide to contact us or make use of personalized services (e.g. by subscribing to a newsletter or by setting your personal preferences for webcast services), then you will be asked to submit the limited personal data which is necessary for us to provide that service or handle your query. This is completely voluntary.

If you ask us to send you newsletters, webcasts or other communications, we rely on your active consent in order to do so. You may opt out of receiving these communications at any time.

If any form which collects your personal data allows you to voluntarily provide additional information, we seek this information because we think it will help us to give you a better quality service. You do not have to provide such information if you do not wish to do so.

We also collect personal data from cookies, which we explain more about below.

### Site traffic information and cookies

On your first visit to this site you were asked (by a notification banner) to accept our use of cookies and similar technologies and we’d like to explain how we use these technologies.

To learn about what cookies and similar technologies are, we recommend that you visit the following third-party website: <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

Like many websites, we use cookies for a variety of purposes. These technologies collect information about your device hardware and interactions with our site.

This information helps us to

  * continuously improve our site’s content and functionality by analyzing where, on which types of devices and how our site is used, how many visitors we receive, and where they click through to the site from; and
  * remember you in case you re-visit our site, so we will know if you have already been served with cookie banners, surveys, or (where site content is undergoing testing) which version of the content you were served.

To delete or stop cookies being placed on your computer, please check the help menu of your internet browser. Blocking cookies will reduce the functionality of this website.

### Activity Log

**_This feature only records activities of a site’s registered users, and the retention duration of activity data will depend on the site’s plan and activity type._**

**Data Used:** To deliver this functionality and record activities around site management, the following information is captured: user email address, user role, user login, user display name, WordPress.com and local user IDs, the activity to be recorded, the WordPress.com-connected site ID of the site on which the activity takes place, the site’s Jetpack version, and the timestamp of the activity. Some activities may also include the actor’s IP address (login attempts, for example) and user agent.

**Activity Tracked:** Login attempts/actions, post and page update and publish actions, comment/pingback submission and management actions, plugin and theme management actions, widget updates, user management actions, and the modification of other various site settings and options. Retention duration of activity data depends on the site’s plan and activity type. [See the complete list of currently-recorded activities (along with retention information)](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/activity-log/#data-retention).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Successful and failed login attempts, which will include the actor’s IP address and user agent.

* * *

### Ads

**_This feature is only available to sites on the Premium and Professional plans._**

**Data Used:** The following information (made available from the visitor’s browser) is collected and sent to Automattic’s Demand Partners: IP address, geographical data (derived from the IP address), user agent, operating system, device type, unique user ID (randomly generated identifier), current URL, and IAB (Interactive Advertising Bureau) interest category. Log data (IP address, geographical data, user agent, operating system, device type) is stored for 30 days. The unique user ID is stored in cookies and is retained for 1 year.

**Activity Tracked:** Ad impressions, video-related events (i.e. pause, mute, 100% plays, etc.) or errors, and ad click events. Various cookies are used for the following purposes: delivering targeted advertisements to specific visitors, storing user identifiers, and collecting anonymous ad platform stats.

* * *

### Carousel

**_Image views are only recorded if the site owner, has explicitly enabled image view stats tracking for this feature via the`jetpack_enable_carousel_stats` filter._**

**Data Used:** If image view tracking is enabled, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Image views.

* * *

**_This feature is only accessible to users logged in to WordPress.com._**

**Data Used:** In order to process a comment like, the following information is used: WordPress.com user ID/username (you must be logged in to use this feature), the local site-specific user ID (if the user is signed in to the site on which the like occurred), and a true/false data point that tells us if the user liked a specific comment. If you perform a like action from [one of our mobile apps](https://apps.wordpress.com/mobile/), some additional information is used to track the activity: IP address, user agent, timestamp of event, blog ID, browser language, country code, and device info.

**Activity Tracked:** Comment likes.

* * *

### Contact Form

**Data Used:** If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the contact form submission data — IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message — is submitted to the [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. the site author who published the page on which the contact form resides). This email will include the submitter’s IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Post and post meta data associated with a user’s contact form submission. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, the IP address and user agent originally submitted with the comment are synced, as well, as they are stored in post meta.

* * *

### Google Analytics

**_This feature is only available to sites on the Premium and Professional plans._**

**Data Used:** Please refer to the appropriate [Google Analytics documentation](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsTrackingOverview#howAnalyticsGetsData) for the specific type of data it collects. For sites running [WooCommerce](https://woocommerce.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) and this feature simultaneously and having all purchase tracking explicitly enabled, purchase events will send Google Analytics the following information: order number, product id and name, product category, total cost, and quantity of items purchased. Google Analytics does offer [IP anonymization](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en), which can be enabled by the site owner.

**Activity Tracked:** This feature sends page view events (and potentially [video play events](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting)) over to Google Analytics for consumption. For sites running WooCommerce-powered stores, some additional events are also sent to Google Analytics: shopping cart additions and removals, product listing views and clicks, product detail views, and purchases. Tracking for each specific WooCommerce event needs to be enabled by the site owner.

* * *

### Gravatar Hovercards

**Data Used:** This feature will send a hash of the user’s email address (if logged in to the site or WordPress.com — or if they submitted a comment on the site using their email address that is attached to an active Gravatar profile) to the [Gravatar](https://gravatar.com/) service (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) in order to retrieve their profile image.

* * *

### Infinite Scroll

**Data Used:** In order to record page views via [WordPress.com Stats](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/) (which must be enabled for page view tracking here to work) with additional loads, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Page views will be tracked with each additional load (i.e. when you scroll down to the bottom of the page and a new set of posts loads automatically). If the site owner has enabled [Google Analytics](https://jetpack.com/support/google-analytics/) to work with this feature, a page view event will also be sent to the appropriate Google Analytics account with each additional load.

* * *

**Data Used:** Commenter’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided via the comment form), timestamp, and IP address. Additionally, a jetpack.wordpress.com IFrame receives the following data: WordPress.com blog ID attached to the site, ID of the post on which the comment is being submitted, commenter’s local user ID (if available), commenter’s local username (if available), commenter’s site URL (if available), MD5 hash of the commenter’s email address (if available), and the comment content. If [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) is enabled on the site, the following information is sent to the service for the sole purpose of spam checking: commenter’s name, email address, site URL, IP address, and user agent.

**Activity Tracked:** The comment author’s name, email address, and site URL (if provided during the comment submission) are stored in cookies. [Learn more about these cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#comments).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** All data and metadata (see above) associated with comments. This includes the status of the comment and, if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is enabled on the site, whether or not it was classified as spam by Akismet.

* * *

### Likes

**_This feature is only accessible to users logged in to WordPress.com._**

**Data Used:** In order to process a post like action, the following information is used: IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID (on which the post was liked), post ID (of the post that was liked), user agent, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Post likes.

* * *

### Mobile Theme

**Data Used:** A visitor’s preference on viewing the mobile version of a site.

**Activity Tracked:** A cookie (`akm_mobile`) is stored for 3.5 days to remember whether or not a visitor of the site wishes to view its mobile version. [Learn more about this cookie](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#mobile-theme).

* * *

### Notifications

**_This feature is only accessible to registered users of the site who are logged in to WordPress.com._**

**Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. Some visitor-related information or activity may be sent to the site owner via this feature. This may include: email address, WordPress.com username, site URL, email address, comment content, follow actions, etc.

**Activity Tracked:** Sending notifications (i.e. when we send a notification to a particular user), opening notifications (i.e. when a user opens a notification that they receive), performing an action from within the notification panel (e.g. liking a comment or marking a comment as spam), and clicking on any link from within the notification panel/interface.

* * *

### Protect

**Data Used:** In order to check login activity and potentially block fraudulent attempts, the following information is used: attempting user’s IP address, attempting user’s email address/username (i.e. according to the value they were attempting to use during the login process), and all IP-related HTTP headers attached to the attempting user.

**Activity Tracked:** Failed login attempts (these include IP address and user agent). We also set a cookie (`jpp_math_pass`) for 1 day to remember if/when a user has successfully completed a math captcha to prove that they’re a real human. [Learn more about this cookie.](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#protect)

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** Failed login attempts, which contain the user’s IP address, attempted username or email address, and user agent information.

* * *

### Search

**_This feature is only available to sites on the Professional plan._**

**Data Used:** Any of the visitor-chosen search filters and query data in order to process a search request on the WordPress.com servers.

* * *

### Sharing

**Data Used:** When sharing content via email (this option is only available if [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) is active on the site), the following information is used: sharing party’s name and email address (if the user is logged in, this information will be pulled directly from their account), IP address (for spam checking), user agent (for spam checking), and email body/content. This content will be sent to [Akismet](https://akismet.com/) (also owned by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/)) so that a spam check can be performed. Additionally, if [reCAPTCHA](http://www.google.com/recaptcha) (by Google) is enabled by the site owner, the sharing party’s IP address will be shared with that service. You can find Google’s privacy policy [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

* * *

### Simple Payments

**_This feature is only available to sites on the Premium and Professional plans, and the actual payment processing is handled by PayPal._**

**Data Used:** Transaction amount, transaction currency code, product title, product price, product ID, order quantity, PayPal payer ID, and PayPal transaction ID.

**Activity Tracked:** The PayPal payer ID, transaction ID, and HTTP referrer are sent with a payment completion tracking event that is attached to the site owner.

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** PayPal transaction ID, PayPal transaction status, PayPal product ID, quantity, price, customer email address, currency, and payment button CTA text.

Because payments are processed by PayPal, we recommend reviewing [its privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

* * *

### Subscriptions

**Data Used:** To initiate and process subscriptions, the following information is used: subscriber’s email address and the ID of the post or comment (depending on the specific subscription being processed). In the event of a new subscription being initiated, we also collect some basic server data, including all of the subscribing user’s HTTP request headers, the IP address from which the subscribing user is viewing the page, and the URI which was given in order to access the page (`REQUEST_URI` and `DOCUMENT_URI`). This server data used for the exclusive purpose of monitoring and preventing abuse and spam.

**Activity Tracked:** [Functionality cookies](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#subscriptions) are set for a duration of **347 days** to remember a visitor’s blog and post subscription choices if, in fact, they have an active subscription.

* * *

### Video Hosting

**_This feature is only available to sites on the Premium and Professional plans._**

**Data Used:** For video play tracking via [WordPress.com Stats](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#wordpress-com-stats), the following information is used: viewer’s IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. If [Google Analytics](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#google-analytics) is enabled, video play events will be sent there, as well.

**Activity Tracked:** Video plays.

* * *

### WooCommerce Services

**Data Used:** _For payments with PayPal or Stripe:_ purchase total, currency, billing information. _For taxes:_ the value of goods in the cart, value of shipping, destination address. _For checkout rates:_ destination address, purchased product IDs, dimensions, weight, and quantities. _For shipping labels:_ customer’s name, address as well as the dimensions, weight, and quantities of purchased products.

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** For payments, we send the purchase total, currency and customer’s billing information to the respective payment processor. Please see the respective third party’s privacy policy ([Stripe’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy/) and [PayPal’s Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/privacy/)) for more details. For automated taxes we send the value of goods in the cart, the value of shipping, and the destination address to TaxJar. Please see TaxJar’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.taxjar.com/privacy-policy/) for details about how they handle this information. For checkout rates we send the destination ZIP/postal code and purchased product dimensions, weight and quantities to [USPS](https://www.usps.com/) or [Canada Post](https://www.canadapost.ca/), depending on the service used. For shipping labels we send the customer’s name, address as well as the dimensions, weight, and quantities of purchased products to [EasyPost](https://www.easypost.com/). We also store the purchased shipping labels on our server to make it easy to reprint them and handle support requests.

* * *

### WordPress.com Secure Sign On

**_This feature is only accessible to registered users of the site with WordPress.com accounts._**

**Data Used:** User ID (local site and WordPress.com), role (e.g. administrator), email address, username and display name. Additionally, for activity tracking (see below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** The following usage events are recorded: starting the login process, completing the login process, failing the login process, successfully being redirected after login, and failing to be redirected after login. Several functionality cookies are also set, and these are detailed explicitly in our [Cookie documentation](https://jetpack.com/support/cookies/#sso).

**Data Synced ([?](https://jetpack.com/support/what-data-does-jetpack-sync/)):** The user ID and role of any user who successfully signed in via this feature.

* * *

### WordPress.com Stats

**Data Used:** IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code. _Important:_ The site owner does **not** have access to any of this information via this feature. For example, a site owner can see that a specific post has 285 views, but he/she cannot see which specific users/accounts viewed that post. Stats logs — containing visitor IP addresses and WordPress.com usernames (if available) — are retained by [Automattic](https://automattic.com/) for 28 days and are used for the sole purpose of powering this feature.

**Activity Tracked:** Post and page views, [video plays](https://jetpackme.wordpress.com/support/for-your-privacy-policy/#video-hosting) (if videos are hosted by WordPress.com), outbound link clicks, referring URLs and search engine terms, and country. When this module is enabled, Jetpack also tracks performance on each page load that includes the Javascript file used for tracking stats. This is exclusively for aggregate performance tracking across Jetpack sites in order to make sure that our plugin and code is not causing performance issues. This includes the tracking of page load times and resource loading duration (image files, Javascript files, CSS files, etc.). The site owner has the ability to force this feature [to honor DNT settings of visitors](https://jetpack.com/support/wordpress-com-stats/#honoring-dnt). By default, DNT is currently not honored.

* * *

### WordPress.com Toolbar

**_This feature is only accessible to registered users of the site who are also logged in to WordPress.com._**

**Data Used:** Gravatar image URL of the logged-in user in order to display it in the toolbar and the WordPress.com user ID of the logged-in user. Additionally, for activity tracking (detailed below): IP address, WordPress.com user ID, WordPress.com username, WordPress.com-connected site ID and URL, Jetpack version, user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code.

**Activity Tracked:** Click actions within the toolbar.
